Zoltán Szőcs

(born 1982, Tirgu Mures, Romania)

Esslingen, Germany Address: +49 157 580 94 107 Telephone: zacsek@gmail.com E-mail:



SUMMARY I've started programming at the age of 7, while writing with the pen has not been mastered yet, I already hacked away at the keyboard, copying programs from magazines, and being amazed how they worked.

> Fast-forward three decades, I am still at it, maturing from Basic, through Pascal and C, then working professionally in C++, Java, Ruby and enjoying learning and trying out new things.

SKILLS Ruby, Python, C/C++, Java, Android Development

Docker, Ansible, Git, Agile Development PostgreSQL, MariaDB / MySQL, Sqlite RabbitMQ, Apache ActiveMQ, Apache Kafka

Linux, Vim, Bash/ZSH scripting, SSH administration, OpenSSL

Eclipse, IntelliJ, NetBeans

AWS (S3, EC2, SNS, SQS, CW), Terraform, Sidekiq, Shoryuken Tensorflow, PyTorch

EXPERIENCE

2020 - now **SolarisBank**

Senior Engineer (Ruby, AWS, Sidekiq)

At SolarisBank I am part of the Cards Team, developing

RESTful APIs for internal & partner usage.

2019 - 2020 **KPIT**

Senior Technical Leader (Scrum, Java, Linux)

At KPIT I supported a large offshore Team with technical know-

how and Agile methodologies to achieve our goals.

2015 - 2019 **KPIT** working for Daimler

Senior Technical Leader (Ruby, Java, Linux)

At **KPIT / Daimler** I have developed a new verification tool for internal use, which:

- verifies whether current state of an individual car allows installation/upgrade of an ECU
- calculates software versions of ECUs in car, conforming to multiple rules
- · checks the state of documentation for each car/component through checking all current configurations with the documentation

2014 - 2015 Citi

Quantitative Developer (C++, Linux, Perl, SybaseDB) At ~ I have worked in the ICG Markets Quant Analysis, Analytical Tools team, developing solutions used by the traders inside the company.

- developed MS Excel plugins as a frontend towards traders, through which they could use our backend logic
- developed the backend logic
- maintained the global server infrastructure
- wrote batch jobs to gather daily financial information
- supported the traders with training and technical knowhow

2011 – 2013 LogMeIn Inc.

Senior Software Engineer (Java, Android, C++, Ruby)

At LogMeIn I worked in the Rescue Mobile team, where I developed a remote-diagnostic & control tool for Android phones

- planned & developed a remote access & control solution for Android
- developed server side features to complement the mobile side
- developed a mock-server framework, to enable end-toend testing of mobile features
- worked with multiple OEM manufacturer`s software integration team to integrate the app into their system

2007 – 2011 Intellio Kft.

Software Engineer (C++, Linux)

At Intellio we developed intelligent surveillance cameras, where I:

- ported the existing embedded software codebase to Linux
- developed communications framework & APIs for use in the storage servers
- integrated 3rd party server APIs with our cameras
- built the embedded Linux distribution for the camera

2006 – 2007 Nokia & Nokia Siemens Networks

Software Engineer, Functional Tester (C++, Linux)

At ~ I worked in the Networks section, developing 2G/3G backends.

2004 – 2006 Neogen Srl.

Software Engineer (C++, Linux, PHP, MySQL)

At Neogen I:

- developed the company's intranet in LAMP stack
- designed & implemented a websearch engine, for use with the company's targeted ad program in C++/MySQL

EDUCATION 2000 – 2005 Automation Engineering, MSc

Petru Maior University, Romania

2003 – 2005 Cisco Certified Network Associate

Petru Maior University, Romania

1999 – 2000 German language proficiency 2nd grade

Deutsches Sprachdiplom der Kultusministerkonferenz Zweite Stufe

1996 – 2000 Information Technology

Bolyai Farkas Theoretical Lyceum

LANGUAGES

- Hungarian (Mother tongue)
- English
- German
- Romanian

HOBBIES I spend most of my time with my family, I enjoy skiing, hiking and try to travel a lot. I like to read a lot, learn new things, am a tech-nerd. I'm a big Linux fan.